<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <atom:link href="https://navo.neocities.org/feed-en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <title>The Web of Site</title>
        <link>https://navo.neocities.org/eng.html</link>
        <description>This is where i do things</description>
        <language>en</language>
            <item>
                <title>new song in main page</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 19:29:21 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/eng</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/eng</guid>
                <description type="html">
                    new song in main page &lt;br&gt;
                    &lt;br&gt;
                    that's it
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Mistakes were made</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 20:16:37 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/eng</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/eng</guid>
                <description type="html"> 
                    um........ hi &lt;br&gt;
                    so, this rosst is to make some corrections about somethings i realized today................... &lt;br&gt;
                    about the site changes i said on last blost? it was custom cursors, and i realized the files didn't upload... &lt;br&gt;
                    cuz it's a supporter-only feature................ &lt;br&gt;
                    &lt;br&gt;
                    yeah that's everything i had to say thx bye
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Some Things</title>
                <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 19:13:03 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost12/eng.html</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost12/eng.html</guid>
                <description type="html">
                    Hello hello again (○´∀`)ﾉﾞ★
                    &lt;br&gt;
                    As you may have already seen, there's a little change on the site !!! &lt;br&gt;
                    Nothing big yet, just a little something i've been wanting to do for some time (*′∀`)b &lt;br&gt;
                    I didn't test on everything and i know the cursors don't work on mbed, but i want to keep it simple using only css. That apart, today 
                    we have 
                    &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
                    &lt;h3&gt;&lt;br&gt;.ﾟ+.(*´∀`).+ﾟ.Translation Notes (DQIX).ﾟ+.(´∀`*).+ﾟ.&lt;/h3&gt;
                    (that's why i won't translate to japanese, i don't think it would make sense) &lt;br&gt;
                    That's more a list of words i found strange, but here we go. &lt;br&gt;
                    First thing i noticed, the 
                    &lt;a target="_blank" class="link" href="https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/dragonquest/images/3/33/DQIX_-_Stella.png"&gt;fairy&lt;/a&gt; 
                    uses lots of katakana. Even her name (サンディー/Sandy) uses katakana. And the words she uses are kinda different. By her looks and 
                    speech, i'd dare to say that she's a stereotypical 
                    &lt;a target="_blank" href="https://ja.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E3%82%AE%E3%83%A3%E3%83%AB" class="link"&gt;gyaru&lt;/a&gt;, since the game is old 
                    (2009). Slangs like イケてる (iketeru; sexy/stylish/cool), that i &lt;i&gt;think&lt;/i&gt; that uses the same イケ from イケメン (ikemen; hunk), 
                    あんがと (angato), shortened from ありがとう (arigatō; thanks) and 元カノ (motokano), shortened from 元彼女 (motokanojo), that means 
                    ex-girlfriend. &lt;br&gt;
                    I won't remember all of them because i put every word i didn't know on the same dictionary list :P &lt;br&gt;
                    &lt;br&gt;
                    Besides her, there's the words that &lt;i&gt;seems&lt;/i&gt; not to be used very much, i just dunno if it's because the game's old, because it 
                    happens on mdieval times or because they're too specific and aren't used on daily life. Or i just didn't know them. There's that. &lt;br&gt;
                    • 危なっかしい (abunakashii) - dangerous; same as 危ない (abunai), but seems to be used for something that &lt;i&gt;seems or may be&lt;/i&gt; 
                    dangerous, while the second is used for something that &lt;i&gt;definitely or already&lt;/i&gt; is dangerous. Maybe has something to do with the 
                    auxiliar らしい (rashii)? &lt;br&gt;
                    • 箱舟 (hakobune) - ark; ermm.... not an ark?? It is obviously a 
                    &lt;a href="https://dragon-quest.org/images/e/e6/StarflightExpressFV.png" target="_blank"&gt;train&lt;/a&gt;????? That apart, i think it isn't 
                    used because it's &lt;strong&gt;too specific&lt;/strong&gt;. Where would anyone use it outside, dunno, the bible. Who even builds an ark nowadays.
                    &lt;br&gt;
                    • 前言 (zengen) - previous remarks; literally before (前) and say (言). It's a noun, prolly shouldn't be used because of that. 
                    I think. &lt;br&gt;
                    • 平伏す (hirefusu) - to prostrate oneself before; seems kinda authoritary, i don't think it is used nowadays even when really bowing 
                    before someone. &lt;br&gt;
                    • 呼び込み (yobikomi) - person who calls clients to the store, or the act of doing if it has the auxiliary verb; uses the kanji of 
                    calling and crowd. Thy tried to turn me into walking propaganda... &lt;br&gt;
                    • 魔法使い (mahoutsukai) - magician; a thing i like on japanese is it having neutral words for nearly everything. In this case it is 
                    the neutral for 魔女/魔男 (majo/madan; i don't think the second actually exists but there's poetic license to mix kanjis to create 
                    words and i saw it being used on a recent manga (魔男のイチ; Ichi, the witch)). Verb conjugation and adjectives also don't use pronouns, 
                    so there's more freedom on character writing and speech. But there's also words that socially perceived as used by specific groups, 
                    so using them is seen as if you identify yourself in that group (slangs included). &lt;br&gt;
                    • 息の根を止める (ikinonewotomeru)- lit. to make the breathing/life stop, to kill; here specifically i think it's the king not wanting 
                    to say 殺す (korosu; kill) while his daughter is there. And also cuz he's a king. Anyway, first time i saw this expression till now. 
                    &lt;br&gt;
                    • 口づけ (kuchidzuke) - to kiss; makes sense having a word in japanese for this, but i had only saw キス (kisu) being used, which comes 
                    from english (kiss). Must be dated. Probably. &lt;br&gt;
                    • 口惜しい (kuchioshii) - frustrated; this one is really dated, old version of 悔しい (kuyashii). Propositally used for being medieval, 
                    i think. &lt;br&gt; 
                    • 婚礼 (konrei) - wedding ceremony; don't know if it's dated or specific for something within the wedding, because there is 結婚 
                    (kekkon) that is wedding (verb and noun). &lt;br&gt; 
                    &lt;br&gt;
                    And that's the vocabulary i bring today !! I bookmarked a lot more, but most of them are just words i've never seen before. Like rpg 
                    classes, weapons, UI, and so on. Words that's &lt;i&gt;probably&lt;/i&gt; common on games (at least on old ones) and i've never seen because this 
                    is the first game i play in japanese. I'll try to save words that seem dated on another list from now on to keep it more organized and 
                    &lt;strong&gt;&lt;i&gt;maybe&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; brung these blosts more frequently. &lt;br&gt;
                    &lt;br&gt;
                    And last but not least, i have an announcement to make. We (i) now have a 
                    &lt;span style="color: var(--tertiary-font-color);"&gt;contact email&lt;/span&gt;!!!! &lt;br&gt;
                    &lt;span style="color: var(--tertiary-font-color); font-size: larger; font-weight: bold;"&gt;navomailster@gmail.com&lt;/span&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                    There you can send comments about blosts, complaints, sugestions and so on. Also a alternative for the comments i wanted to make, since 
                    i currently can't pay for hosting an already made system and don't want to mess with data security to make a system with login... &lt;br&gt;
                    &lt;br&gt;
                    Well, that's it for today &lt;br&gt;
                    Cya o/
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Last chost</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 13:00:30 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost11/eng.html</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost11/eng.html</guid>
                <description type="html">
                    This blost doesn't work in rss, please open in another tab.
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Sisters</title>
                <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 16:34:53 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost10/eng.html</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost10/eng.html</guid>
                <description type="html">
                    Blost with some frequency? In my website?? Unlikely. &lt;br&gt;
                    Jokes aside, i finished the rawing i said i was doing :D &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                    &lt;div class="div-imagens"&gt;
                        &lt;img class="expandivel imagem-unica" src="/images/desenhos/trigemeas.webp" alt=""&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;
                        Can't say i'm satisfied with everything, my lack of experience with background and lighting is kinda obvious here :/ &lt;br&gt;
                        And feet. Why is it so hard to draw feet??? Doesn't make sense?? I don't want to draw feet to practice... &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        Also need to do more background interaction, mattress is not supposed to be so plain. &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        Perspective... Is perspective.
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;strong&gt;
                    iframe
                    &lt;\strong&gt;
                    &lt;br&gt;
                    &lt;div class="div-imagens"&gt;
                        &lt;div class="caixa2-3"&gt;
                            &lt;iframe class="iframe-element" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ysRUjwsxa2c?si=_TaxqRQO31qukMCb" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;
                        As you can see i tend to forget background elements a lot. Had to go back sometimes to draw things that was missing in the 
                        timelapse export :) &lt;br&gt;
                        And i have to think more about decoration, there's few. The lack of creativity seeps into the the characters personalities 
                        expression :/ &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        Will take the chance to present them here, they're triplets of a witch family i created. The one in the middle is the "oldest", 
                        Amarilis. The one on the right is the "middle sister", Unxia. The one on the left is the "youngest", Viola. Eventually the rest 
                        of the family will be presented. Eventually.
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>We be fishing</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 17:12:25 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost9/eng.html</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost9/eng.html</guid>
                <description type="html">
                    &lt;h2&gt;GAMES&lt;/h2&gt;
                    recently one thing took a lot of my time. cool fishes. casual games. and baldur's gate but we don't talk about it. &lt;br&gt;
                    &lt;div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; flex-direction: column; align-items: center;"&gt;
                        &lt;img class="expandivel" style="margin: 5px; max-width: 50%;" src="/images/img-blosts/pecando.png" alt=""&gt;
                        &lt;i style="text-align: end; font-size: small;"&gt;Cabas Pecando, 2024&lt;/i&gt;
                    &lt;/div&gt;
                    &lt;p&gt;
                        webfishing is really fun you should try it!! obviously like any social games there's weird, criminal or annoying people, but 
                        you can always ban them! (unless it's a hacker then you can't) &lt;br&gt;
                        there's a lot of fishes and things that aren't fish too, very cool. every one of them have some funsies on description. and 
                        customization!!!! i love customization.
                        &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
                        also started playing Sun Haven, a game about farming and magic(ing). also cool, has more than one city to explore, something 
                        i missed on stardew. i wish three was a desert expansion and more interaction with sandy :( &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        and i'll play Dragon Quest IX in japanese :D &lt;br&gt;
                        the language used in the game is kinda easy, it even shows the kanji's furigana. i'm playing on a 2ds, so it's a fun experience 
                        altough some of the furigana is hard to identify on the small screen... anyway, it'll be a fun study :) i'll try to make some 
                        translation notes to blost here. &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;h2&gt;SITE&lt;/h2&gt;
                        now we have zoom on the pictures!!! just click a image on a blost or the main page. i only put it on images i deemed needed 
                        so no zoom on the funny gifs &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        and about the site change, still no idea XD &lt;br&gt;
                        i want to try putting comments to see what is the tape (bad translation intended) but it seems complicated... well sometime 
                        something will change, no rush. &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        and that's it for today, cya o/
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Music</title>
                <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 20:32:45 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost8/eng.html</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost8/eng.html</guid>
                <description type="html">
                    &lt;p style="display: flex; flex-direction: column;"&gt;
                        so &lt;br&gt;
                        ha ha, hello. no, i didn't die, i was just beaten by my lack of frequncy and things to talk about XD &lt;br&gt;
                        coming from the last post, the music is done (not exactly but i won't be changing anything cuz i gave myself a deadline and intend 
                        to respect it) and it is here !! &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;iframe style="align-self: center; margin: 1vh;" width="300" height="300" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hBzjVycVEgs?si=EUi2aL0LF8iBl62J" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
                        lots of things i'd change buuuuuuut it's best to move on to the next so i have more experiences. &lt;br&gt;
                        available on 
                        &lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://on.soundcloud.com/L2yJXU4jpTb268cX6"&gt;bandcamp&lt;/a&gt;, 
                        &lt;a href="https://music.youtube.com/watch?v=hBzjVycVEgs"&gt;youtube music&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://on.soundcloud.com/L2yJXU4jpTb268cX6"&gt;soundcloud&lt;/a&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;p&gt;
                            &lt;br&gt;
                            and, will write it here to put pression on myself so i actually do it, i will make some layout changes, some thing i want to 
                            change. may not be next post's topic, but will eventually come. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                            also i have a kinda big drawing in progress, maybe i'll finish it this year :O (actually two but we don't talk about the 
                            other one) &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
                            and that is it. i would say "till next week" but we both know that's probably a lie &lt;br&gt;
                            later o/
                        &lt;/p&gt;
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Report #2</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 22:24:15 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost7/index.html</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost7/index.html</guid>
                <description type="html">
                    &lt;p&gt;
                        ehem &lt;br&gt;
                        i said i an making a music, right?? so.... this is how it is doing till now 👍 &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cDz3TzCmS9M?si=Q4hzjXUffsqsy488"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        i think it is needless to say i'm still a beginner. this is the fourth (?) thing i'm doing fr, and surely the best one until now. &lt;br&gt;
                        i also relied less on the base sample !!! i think &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        a late blost again but that's it, cya o/
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>popipo_sketch.mp4</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2024 20:41:13 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/eng.html</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/eng.html</guid>
                <description type="html">
                    new thing on main page! &lt;br&gt;
                    it's an iframe, so you'll need to go there to see &lt;br&gt;
                    or click &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/Fie-ZyQDA0E"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Report #1</title>
                <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 13:14:42 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost5/eng.html</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost5/eng.html</guid>
                <description type="html">
                    &lt;p&gt;
                        recently i've been doing an animation, maybe you know where it comes from it's a bit famous (joke) &lt;/div&gt;
                        (iframe here, maybe won't load)
                        &lt;div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;"&gt;
                            &lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ets4Rz2ddo4?si=1eJNnM1Ve6rordST" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;            &lt;p&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        i'm doing this to learn a bit more, i need practice and have zero ideas to animate so i thought maybe this would help.
                        dunno if it will leave the sketch fase but probably it will be only on december, i have another project i &lt;strong&gt;need&lt;/strong&gt; to finish this year. &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        it's a music, and a great idea for compost #6 but i had it after it ended :( &lt;br&gt;
                        i will really try to finish thism but with my lack of experience and creativity i can't promise anything. &lt;br&gt;
                        i don't want to spoiler it but also can't raise expectations what do  do o_O &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        anyway, i'll do this kinda post when i have nothing to post on the week, and try to make on post a week at least &lt;br&gt;
                        till next time o/
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Fungi Sightings! ! #1</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 12:23:29 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost4/eng.html</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost4/eng.html</guid>
                <description type="html">
                    &lt;p&gt;
                        &lt;div class="div-imagens"&gt;
                            &lt;img class="imagem-dupla" src="/images/img-blosts/fungo1.webp" alt=""&gt;
                            &lt;img class="imagem-dupla" src="/images/img-blosts/fungo2.webp" alt=""&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div class="div-imagens"&gt;
                            &lt;img class="imagem-dupla" src="/images/img-blosts/fungo3.webp" alt=""&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        Seen this saturday 12/10&lt;br&gt;
                        It seems to a 10 meter radius colony, few mushrooms but a good distance between them &lt;br&gt;
                        I don't know how to identify mushrooms (yet) but &lt;i&gt;apparently&lt;/i&gt; it's from the Agaricus genus &lt;br&gt;
                        Also couldn't get a sample cuz someone killed it :( &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        small blost but that's it for the wek, cya o/
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>We have RSS now!!!</title>
                <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 15:29:16 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost3/eng.html</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost3/eng.html</guid>
                <description type="html">
                    &lt;p&gt;
                        &lt;div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;"&gt;&lt;img style="margin: 5px; max-width: 100%;" src="/images/img-blosts/chokante.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                        It's an improvised one i made, there's one for each language. (pages with x language redirect to it's own rss) &lt;br&gt;
                        I intend to make, sometimes, posts exclusive to one language, since some things really can't be translated without losing it's 
                        meaning (haiku, for example) &lt;br&gt;
                        Maybe some rosts (rss exclusive posts) who knows (says the one who barely posts normally). &lt;br&gt;
                        For the time being, it has only the blosts. Blog aside, i will also put the index's things i post from here on &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        Until then, see ya o/
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>Culinary Club</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 12:08:28 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost2/eng.html</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost2/eng.html</guid>
                <description type="html">
                    &lt;p&gt;
                        Remember that i'm studying japanese? So, the school i got a one year scholarship is a "language and culture school". 
                        I'm currently on the sewing club (were sewing a happi, will post about it sometime later) and sometimes we have a culinary class. 
                        I beg for the cooking gods' forgiveness cuz i suck at plate presentation. (also at taking pictures but that's another story)&lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        Last time (that i didn't post) we made gyōza, harusame salad and miso soup &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
                            &lt;img style="margin: 5px; max-width: 50%;" src="/images/culinaria/receitaG.webp" alt=""&gt;
                            &lt;img style="margin: 5px; max-width: 50%;" src="/images/culinaria/gyouza.webp" alt=""&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        This time we made takoyaki, onigiri and yakitori. &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
                            &lt;img style="margin: 5px; max-width: 50%;" src="/images/culinaria/receita1.webp" alt=""&gt;
                            &lt;img style="margin: 5px; max-width: 50%;" src="/images/culinaria/receita2.webp" alt=""&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
                            &lt;img style="margin: 5px; max-width: 50%;" src="/images/culinaria/prato2.webp" alt=""&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;h3&gt;Getting ready&lt;/h3&gt;
                        First we did the takoyaki and yakitori sauces. &lt;br&gt;
                        Since we were in 12, i had to count &lt;strong&gt;50&lt;/strong&gt; spoonfuls of shōyu, plus 30 of sugar and 10 of sake (the cooking one). 
                        Then we boiled the sake to get the alcohol out, then added the shōyu and sugar. &lt;br&gt;
                        After it started to grow we took it off the stove and lowered the heat to put it again. 
                        Since we don't have a centennial tare, we just took out a bit of the foam. &lt;br&gt;
                        (I didn't see the takoyaki sauce being made so i can't describe it's recipe :/) &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        Then we got to cut the chicken breast. &lt;br&gt;
                        First take the skin bits out, then cut off the most thick edge, and last but not least cut in half the remaining breast. 
                        The thin part of these two halves will be in the end of the stick, so when cutting the three parts in bite-sized bits make sure to split them. 
                        At the same time other people where cutting the green onion for both the takoyaki and yakitori, thinly for the first and long for the other.
                        &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;h3&gt;Putting it together&lt;/h3&gt;
                        For the takoyaki dough you will need eggs, flour, water and the green onions (we also put some teeny tiny shrimpies but i &lt;i&gt;think&lt;/i&gt; that is optional?). &lt;br&gt;
                        Mix first the water and eggs, then slowly add the flour while mixing, and lastly the green onions and shrimps. &lt;br&gt;
                        After this, cut the octopus in tiny bits that will fit in a takoyaki ball (something around half to one centimeter i think)&lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
                            &lt;img style="margin: 5px; max-width: 50%;" src="/images/culinaria/takoyaki1.webp" alt=""&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        For the yakitori we measured 4~5 fingers before the round edge of the stick to have where to grasp.
                        Then, in the same direction the chicken's fibers go, we pierced it. It is quite simple, first one of the thick chicken bits then a green onion, and repeat.
                        When getting close to the sharp tip (around 2 fingers), you put one of the thin chicken cut, but since it is thin you put it folded. &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
                            &lt;img style="margin: 5px; max-width: 50%;" src="/images/culinaria/yakitori1.webp" alt=""&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        The rice for the onigiri is the easiest, since the teacher got an electric rice cooker. &lt;br&gt;
                        A handful of rice is enough, so put this much in a bowl using a spoon. 
                        Then wet your hands with water and get some salt on those hands. &lt;br&gt;
                        Now take the rice and start shaping it with your hands. If you want a filling, put it in the middle before shaping. &lt;br&gt;
                        To shape, basically make a triangle with each of your hands. The upper one sideways and the lower one pointed fowards. Then press and spin. &lt;br&gt;
                        And you're done! If you want, put some furikake or a nori on it. &lt;br&gt; 
                        &lt;div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
                            &lt;img style="margin: 5px; max-width: 33%;" src="/images/culinaria/onigiri.webp" alt=""&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;h3&gt;"Yaki-ing 'em Ts"&lt;/h3&gt;
                        We were in groups, and mine was the first in the onigiri (result above). &lt;br&gt;
                        After that we went to the takoyaki machine.
                        &lt;div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; max-width: 100%; align-items: center;"&gt;
                            &lt;img style="margin: 5px; max-width: 33%;" src="/images/culinaria/takoyaki2.webp" alt=""&gt;
                            &lt;div style="max-width: 33%;"&gt;
                                &lt;img style="margin: 5px; max-width: 100%;" src="/images/culinaria/takoyaki3.webp" alt=""&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        Nothing much to say here, just put the dough and wait for it to be firm enough to turn around with a stick (i suck at this). &lt;br&gt;
                        The heat didn't spread well so the ones on the edges took longer to finish. &lt;br&gt;
                        Then take it off and put the sauce (that i didn't see the making). 
                        If you want you can put some mayo and that thingie that sizzle when the takoyaki is hot (also didn't get the name srry T_T) &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        Then the tori.
                        &lt;div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; max-width: 100%; align-items: center;"&gt;
                            &lt;div style="margin: 5px; max-width: 33%;"&gt;
                                &lt;img style="max-width: 100%;" src="/images/culinaria/yakitori2.webp" alt=""&gt;
                            &lt;/div&gt;
                            &lt;img style="margin: 5px; max-width: 33%;" src="/images/culinaria/yakitori3.webp" alt=""&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        Also quite simple. Just take care to not burn your hands when turning their sides, cuz damn coal sure is hot (to the touch). &lt;br&gt;
                        I don't have a picture of we putting the sauce, but when it's browned on the four sides you wet all the sides with sauce and put back in the grill.
                        Since it has sugar, just a bit of time on the heat is sufficient. Take it off and it's ready to eat! &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        Here's a well made plate (not mine)
                        &lt;div style="display: flex; justify-content: center; max-width: 100%;"&gt;
                            &lt;img style="margin: 5px; max-width: 50%;" src="/images/culinaria/prato-decente.webp" alt=""&gt;
                        &lt;/div&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;h3&gt;It was fine&lt;/h3&gt;
                        I think i don't like seafood that much. Idk, something in the flavor just don't click with me. &lt;br&gt;
                        It wasn't bad, but for me it isn't something i would go after to eat on a regular basis. &lt;br&gt;
                        The yakitori is great, will make at home eventually (still need a grill, a beetle hubcap will suffice) &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;

                        &lt;h3&gt;See ya next time o/&lt;/h3&gt;
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                </description>
            </item>
            <item>
                <title>First blost! (blog + post)</title>
                <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 12:08:28 BRT</pubDate>
                <link>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost1/eng.html</link>
                <guid>https://navo.neocities.org/blog/blosts/blost1/eng.html</guid>
                <description type="html">
                    &lt;p&gt;
                        &lt;div style="display: flex; justify-content: center;"&gt;&lt;img style="margin: 5px;" src="https://media1.tenor.com/m/05QmcJhoSIcAAAAC/cat-silly-hello.gif" alt=""&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
                        Hi o/ &lt;br&gt;
                        Here i will post some thingies that i'm currently doing or thinking, will be very non-professional and &lt;i&gt;maybe&lt;/i&gt; with translations 
                        (don't expect much from me)&lt;br&gt;
                        I'll use the main page as an art storage and portfolio&lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        So basically what i'll post here: &lt;br&gt;
                        • Extras (?) about the things in the main page. &lt;br&gt;
                        • Sometimes translations for training. &lt;br&gt;
                        • Gossip 💅 (rare)&lt;br&gt;
                        • Maybe css/js crimes (even rarer) &lt;br&gt;
                        • Announcements (the rarest)&lt;br&gt;
                        • Comments about what i'm watching/reading atm (maybe??? i don't usually do it but will try) &lt;br&gt;
                        &lt;br&gt;
                        That's about it, see you in the next blost!! o/
                    &lt;/p&gt;
                </description>
            </item>
    </channel>
</rss>